<doc id="14fbeb82a73a7df37bcda0583c9bca7e">
<headline> </headline>
<post author="TG123" datetime="2013-02-09T11:02:00" id="p1">
The "punishment" of Fayhan al Ghamdi for viciously beating, raping and burning his innocent 5 year old daughter who this sick and twisted man suspected of not being a virgin... a fifty thousand dollar fine and time served... is an offense to God and every decent human being alike.

It is also an extreme hypocrisy that in Saudi Arabia, a man cannot be executed for killing his children or wife, but can face the death penalty for leaving Islam and becoming a Christian (or a member of any other religion).

The World Muslim Congress came out with a statement decrying both the murder and the "punishment" (if it can be called that). While I do not agree with them that the Quran is God's word or that Muhammad is his prophet, everything else they said regarding the case is dead-on, in my opinion.

I agree with them that capital punishment is wrong, albeit not only for the reasons they gave (which I think are good ones) but also because God clearly said in the Bible that those who do not show mercy will not be shown mercy by God.

The Saudi rapist Fayhan al-Ghamdi, got away with murder

The intention of Sharia law was to serve justice to the parties in conflict, it is human interpretation of God's word to suit their era, it is not a divine law, neither is it God's law as propagated. However, it is the abuse in administering the Sharia law that is the problem. Unfortunately, the Sharia law is so distorted that it sounds like a cruel system of law to a woman who gets thrown out on the whim of an idiot by calling Talaq three times, female rape victim, an apostate and the blasphemer.

Those men you have listed, "Imam Hanifa, Imam Shafi, Imam Hanbal, Imam Malik, Imam Ghazali or Imam Madoodi," were great men with a few exceptions for their time.

They defined the Sharia in terms of the norms prevalent at that time. With all due respect and honor for their work, they did not have the same environment as Prophet Muhammad did or we have, - of working with different tribes and faiths, and as a result their attitudes were "stick it to them".

This man, Fayhan al-Ghamdi got away paying the blood money. He should have been locked away, as they say in Urdu "Qaid ba-mushaqqat" prison with hard labor. What prevents the SOB from repeating it? If he has the money to shell out again, he will do it again. I n the US there are many incidents where a hard core criminal was let out on bail, and he would do go out and do the same.

I am personally against the state killing the criminal deliberately, it denies the criminal from living the life, and prevents him from repenting his mistake.... and the blood money does not bring justice, compensation should be there to the victims, but that should be a part of whole punishment. We cannot trade life for money.

Only God's word is beyond question, Prophet's words, if genuine, would be unquestionable. A lot has been dished out as Prophet's word. I come across so much non-sense ascribed to him. He was the ultimate peace maker and rightfully called Rahmatul Aalameen -the mercy to mankind.

Muslims do not uphold that title for him; they are brutal towards those who convert from Islam to other faiths, or blasphemers. Some Muslims are very insecure in their faith, they think that Prophet will disappear into thin air if someone criticizes him, or not defended. Prophet Muhammad (pbuh) is beyond defending. Some of the Imams did not have faith in the prophet and resorted to defending him, how wrong are they!

Be hopeful, things will change for better, the new generation will restore common sense to the religion which is about fairness, justness and respect for God's creation. Islam is about freedom and not compulsion.

URL - <a href="http://worldmuslimcongress.blogspot.com/2013/02/the-saudi-rapist-fayhan-al-ghamdi-got.html">World Muslim Congress : The Saudi rapist Fayhan al-Ghamdi, got away with murder</a>

Mike Ghouse
Muslims Together building cohesive societies.
<a href="http://www.WorldMuslimCongress.com">World Muslim Congress</a>

<a href="http://worldmuslimcongress.blogspot.ca/2013/02/the-saudi-rapist-fayhan-al-ghamdi-got.html">World Muslim Congress : The Saudi rapist Fayhan al-Ghamdi, got away with murder</a>
</post>
</doc>