<doc id="17a2dc40635ec239e9e16d10b6dd45e8">
<headline> </headline>
<post author="xchrom" datetime="2014-04-19T07:08:00" id="p1">
<a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/health/archive/2014/04/rio-is-literally-swimming-in-poop/360860/">http://www.theatlantic.com/health/archive/2014/04/rio-is-literally-swimming-in-poop/360860/</a>

<img src="http://cdn.theatlantic.com/static/newsroom/img/mt/2014/04/AP111578053729/lead.jpg"/> ?n48hy7
A protester with the organization Meu Rio in January in Ipanema. (Felipe Dana/AP)

RIO DE JANEIRO  Tall and tan and young and lovely, the girl from Ipanema goes  Ew, whats that smell?

At Ipanema beach in January, the organization Meu Rio staged a protest in an attempt to make it known that thousands of gallons of raw sewage are dumped into the ocean off Rios coast each day.

For three months we held protests every weekend to turn an invisible problem into a visible one, Leona Deckelbaum, the campaign coordinator with Meu Rio, said in a recent interview. Only about 34 percent of Rios sewage is treated, and the rest simply washes into the azure waters, giving new meaning to the nautical term poop deck.

Guanabara Bay, the site of several 2016 Olympic sailing events, has 78 times Brazils legally allowed limit of fecal pollution, and 195 times the U.S. limit. In addition to human waste, the bay is also a receptacle for trash from ships and the bay's 15 adjacent communities, as well as toxic runoff from a former landfill. And its not just Guanabarathe ritzy Leblon and Ipanema beach areas are plagued with similar pollution problems. The state environmental agency, INEA, found that Leblon and Ipanema were unfit for swimming for 40 percent of 2011. Botafogo Beach had so much fecal pollution that it did not pass a single INEA test in 2013, according to the BBC.
</post>
<post author="Demeter" datetime="2014-04-19T08:44:00" id="p2">
1. After Beijing, nobody cares
</post>
<post author="DinahMoeHum" datetime="2014-04-19T09:14:00" id="p3">
2. Not just sailing events; open-water distance swimming and triathlon events are also affected by this.
</post>
</doc>